# James Paschall

# Senior DevOps Engineer

(206)499-7442 | beautuesday@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamestuesdaypaschall/ | Seattle, WA

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMERY

Technically proficient and meticulous Senior DevOps Engineer with 6+ years of experience. An established leader and key contributor to both of Airbiquity's Global Operations and Cloud Platform teams, playing a pivotal role on two major OEM platforms. Recognized expert resource utilized by cross-functional teams to analyze application or infrastructure code, address networking challenges, optimize AWS resources, and more. My proficiency enables me to provide rapid and effective solutions, coupled with clear communication to disseminate optimal proposals across multiple teams.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Senior DevOps Engineer | Airbiquity | December 2021 - Present

Global Operations Team

- Championed and actively contributed to the implementation of AWS
   Organizations, centralizing the management of 23 accounts. This initiative
   resulted in a 75% increase in control and 100% improvement in observability.
- Collaborated with corporate IT to integrate Single Sign-On (SSO) with corporate Active Directory (AD) users, eliminating necessity for IAM user management, enhancing security measures and streamlining user experience for developers.
- Mentored and trained team members in Terraform best practices, IaC methodologies, and modern infrastructure design principles, fostering a culture of knowledge sharing and skill development within the team.
- Led the breakdown IaC knowledge silos within the team empowering all members to contribute, resulting in 100% of project goals being met monthover-month in 2023.
- Implemented Git branching management, strategies, and training to manage infrastructure code with GitLab for the Global Operations team and developers on the SDP Application teams.
- Played a key role in developing and maintaining extensive documentation covering system architecture, processes, and procedures. Advocated for increased utilization of roadmaps, runbooks, and documentation, actively steering the team from reliance on tribal knowledge to a more structured and well-documented knowledge base on Confluence and enhancing report readability on tickets in Jira.

#### Cloud Platform Team

- Acting SME on Terraform and Airbiquity's Infrastructure, developing and maintaining automation scripts resulting in a 30% reduction in manual effort and a 25% increase in team productivity.
- Led initiatives to refactor legacy infrastructure code around GitLab CI/CD pipeline, resulting in a 50% reduction in development and deployment times while enhancing scalability and reliability.
- Spearheaded the refactoring of a critical project, focusing on optimizing automation strategies and reducing development and deployment cycles, reducing deployment time from 5 days to 4 hours.
- Designed infrastructure architecture for one of the major OEMs with multitenancy, adhering and modifying established policies and procedures for providing delivery of infrastructure and application features to customers without destabilizing production environments.
- Orchestrated the deployment and management of the company's infrastructure using Terraform and IaC principles, enabling seamless provisioning of resources in AWS.
- Implemented and designed robust security measures, including hardened OS configurations and AWS secrets management, ensuring compliance with industry standards and significantly fortifying the company's infrastructure against potential threats. This effort led to a significant decrease in security vulnerabilities, maintaining over 95% in CIS Benchmarks.
- Strategized in cross-team meetings to design, develop, and implement wellorchestrated features into existing architecture.

# Systems Engineer | Airbiquity | March 2020 - December 2021

- Managed and maintained global data centers and Network Operations Centers (NOC) with tier 3 support, ensuring seamless operations and high availability across diverse geographical locations.
- Proficiently administered predominantly Linux-based systems, supplemented by a subset of Windows-based systems.
- Led on-call shifts, promptly addressing critical incidents to minimize downtime and maintain service-level agreements (SLAs) with a 99.9% first response and resolution within or before severity windows.
- Utilized various monitoring tools (OpsView, DataDog, CloudWatch, etc) for proactive analysis, troubleshooting, and performance optimization.
- Oversaw DNS infrastructure, optimizing configurations for performance and reliability.
- Assumed responsibility overseeing the management of AWS IAM users and corporate AD users for the team, resulting in a notable 25% increase in the team's productivity on other tasks.

# Consultant / Developer | Freelance | July 2018 - March 2020

Contact: The Morning Blunt

- Advised and executed layout and design enhancements, significantly enriching user experience.
- Engineered a user-friendly navigation menu and layout, resulting in improved user interaction.
- Implemented a structured multi-page subject approach, elevating readability and accessibility.
- Spearheaded SEO improvements, resulting in higher search engine rankings and increased organic traffic.
- Offered guidance for future post optimization.

#### **EDUCATION**

- Certificate in Full Stack Web Development | Coding Dojo, Bellevue
- Certificate in Editing | University of Washington, Seattle

## **CORE COMPETENCIES**

Process Improvement | Training & Development | Policy Adherence | Data Security |
Operations Management | Cross-functional Team Leadership | Cross-team
Collaboration | Troubleshooting | Problem Solving | User Experience Improvement

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Terraform | Infrastructure as Code (IaC) | HCL | YAML | BASH | Automation | SSM | Amazon Web Services (AWS) | Network Administration | DNS Management | Agile & DevOps Methodologies | Version Control | Git | Ansible | Linux | Jenkins | Virtualization | Scripting | Programming | Python | Configuration Management